<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Littleroot on</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/</link><description>Recent content in Littleroot on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Definitions/</guid><description>Orbitals: Area of space that is likely to contain electrons
Cathode Ray Tube: A high vacuum tube in which cathode rays produce luminous images on a fluorescent screen</description></item><item><title/><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Missed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Missed/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/backup/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Untitled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Untitled/</guid><description/></item><item><title>04-04-2023 Perth Pokémon Regional Championships 2023</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/04-04-2023-perth-pokemon-regional-championships-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/04-04-2023-perth-pokemon-regional-championships-2023/</guid><description>go back
Written on 3rd-4th April 2023.
Introduction So&amp;hellip;as a hobby, I play a funny little game called Pokémon. You might&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it.</description></item><item><title>06-06-2023 Jacaranda Test</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/06-06-2023-jacaranda-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/06-06-2023-jacaranda-test/</guid><description>go back
does this work
please tell me it does
surely
nottacoz my saving grace
bless me with your presence</description></item><item><title>07-05-2023-Ranting</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/07-05-2023-Ranting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/07-05-2023-Ranting/</guid><description>go back
My friends have a plan involving me. I was told that I would have to make a big decision.</description></item><item><title>12-05-2023 A Dialogue of Epic Proportions</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/12-05-2023-a-dialogue-of-epic-proportions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/12-05-2023-a-dialogue-of-epic-proportions/</guid><description>go back
yes, all (mis)spellings are intentional.
a dialogue between me and ed about intelligence
ed: we are geniuses man what are your thughts on that</description></item><item><title>12-05-2023 Spec problems I could solve that edward couldn't</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/12-05-2023-spec-problems-i-could-solve-that-edward-couldnt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/12-05-2023-spec-problems-i-could-solve-that-edward-couldnt/</guid><description>go back
Proof by Counterexample $$\forall{n}\in \mathbb{N}; 2n^2-4n+31\in P$$ For this, we must show that there exists a natural number $n$, such that $2n^2-4m+31$ is not a prime number, i.</description></item><item><title>13-05-2023 A bill of town</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/13-05-2023-a-bill-of-town/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/13-05-2023-a-bill-of-town/</guid><description>go back
Preface Presently we live in an assumed democracy. The democratic system is in place, however it is ambiguous and not defined.</description></item><item><title>14-05-2023 A funny conversation I found</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/14-05-2023-a-funny-conversation-i-found/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/14-05-2023-a-funny-conversation-i-found/</guid><description>go back
replacing it with people in the town because it was funny
Jonathan: Would you guys be there for me if I was going through something?</description></item><item><title>17-05-2023 Some thoughts on life</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/17-05-2023-some-thoughts-on-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/17-05-2023-some-thoughts-on-life/</guid><description>go back
I&amp;rsquo;m high on anger and no sleep.
Right now, life isn&amp;rsquo;t as great as it could be.</description></item><item><title>24-05-2023 Ajay's Table Dilemma</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/24-05-2023-ajays-table-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/24-05-2023-ajays-table-dilemma/</guid><description>go back
Paraphrased very slightly.
So. This is quite an interesting image, isn&amp;rsquo;t it. My best friend Ajay Bisnath, Student Councillor of Perth Modern, has started to use Obsidian.</description></item><item><title>24-07-2023 Taco Cat Goat Cheese Pizza</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/24-07-2023-taco-cat-goat-cheese-pizza/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/24-07-2023-taco-cat-goat-cheese-pizza/</guid><description>go back
i&amp;rsquo;m the best
taco
cat
goat
cheese
pizza
i&amp;rsquo;m actually cracked at this game
highly recommend
fun fact: tacocat is a palindrome</description></item><item><title>25-05-2023 Should I stay or should I go</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/25-05-2023-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/25-05-2023-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</guid><description>go back
Like the hit song &amp;ldquo;Should I Stay or Should I Go&amp;rdquo; by The Clash?
But seriously.
I&amp;rsquo;m in a bit of a pickle right now.</description></item><item><title>26-05-2023 Nuke orphans</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/26-05-2023-nuke-orphans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/26-05-2023-nuke-orphans/</guid><description>go back
A very good Obsidian plugin.
What did you think I meant?
Jeez, that&amp;rsquo;s some dark stuff in your mind.</description></item><item><title>31-03-2023 The Fred Tendency Hypothesis (FTH)</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/31-03-2023-the-fred-tendency-hypothesis-fth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/31-03-2023-the-fred-tendency-hypothesis-fth/</guid><description>go back
Authors Christian Ed Jonathan Dasindu Hypothesis If something exists (has matter), it shall then tend towards either Anthony Du or Frederick Yap.</description></item><item><title>A few books I would recommend reading</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/16-05-2023-a-few-books-i-recommend-reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/16-05-2023-a-few-books-i-recommend-reading/</guid><description>go back
not including manga, I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight those later
The Inheritance Cycle, by Christopher Paolini This is a book, reminiscent of Lord of the Rings, but in my opinion, better.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/AboutMe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/AboutMe/</guid><description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Jonathan. I made this website as a side project.
Right now, as of 2023, I&amp;rsquo;m in year 11, doing ATAR.</description></item><item><title>Acids and Bases</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AcidsandBases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AcidsandBases/</guid><description>go back
Salt: Substance formed when hydrogen in an acid is substituted by a metal ion
For a group 1 metal M: $M^+$</description></item><item><title>Alkanes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Alkanes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Alkanes/</guid><description> go back
Hydrocarbons Organic Molecule: any molecule that contains carbon Hydrocarbon: molecule containing only hydrogen and carbon Alkanes Hydrocarbon with all single bonds Thus, it is a saturated hydrocarbon $C_n H_{2n+2}$ Chemical Properties of Alkanes Not reactive However, it will react with certain substances in certain conditions Substitution reactions Halogenation (reaction with halogen) $CH_4+Cl_2\rightarrow CH_3Cl + HCl$ Not Hydrochloric acid Hydrogen Chloride Combustion Fuel burns in oxygen Exothermic reaction Complete combustion: there is an excess of $O_2$ $O_2 + x \rightarrow CO_2 + H_2O+energy$ Incomplete combustion: there is a limited supply of $O_2$ $O_2+x \rightarrow CO+H_2O+energy$ $O_2+x \rightarrow C+H_2O+energy$</description></item><item><title>Application of Demand and Supply - Price Controls</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/pricecontrols/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/pricecontrols/</guid><description>go back
Price Floor Minimum price (lower price limit) allowed by legislation Government believes equilibrium price is too low Prices of all affected goods or services transacted cannot be below the minimum price allowed For a price floor to be effective, the legislated price, $P_{min}$, must be above the market equilibrium price Surplus occurs, as $Q_{supplied}&amp;gt;Q_{demanded}$ Quantity transacted will fall Consumer surplus will fall With government intervention, producers can earn more A minimum wage may help reduce the income gap between higher and lower wage earners Price Ceiling Opposite of a price floor Maximum price (upper price limit) allowed by legislation Prices of all affected goods or services transacted cannot be above the maximum price allowed For a price ceiling to be effective, the legislated price $P_{max}$ must be below the equilibrium price Shortage occurs, as $Q_{demanded} &amp;gt; Q_{supplied}$ What alternative means of resource allocation can replace the price mechanism, now that a price ceiling is imposed?</description></item><item><title>Application of Demand and Supply - Taxes and Subsidies</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/taxesandsubsidies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/taxesandsubsidies/</guid><description>go back
Tax: Money payed to the government by firms
Types of Tax Direct tax Income/wealth tax Paid by households or firms directly to the government Personal income tax Corporate tax Indirect tax Tax on Goods/Services Paid indirectly to the government via the sellers of the good Taxed on profit, not revenue Specific tax Ad valorem tax Example is General Sales Tax (GST) Indirect Tax Shifts the supply curve up by the amount of tax imposed Specific Tax Good or service is taxed a fixed amount per unit e.</description></item><item><title>Articles</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Articles/</guid><description>Get it? It&amp;rsquo;s art?
In a DD-MM-YYYY format.
Just some thoughts and articles that I publish
31-03-2023 The Fred Tendency Hypothesis (FTH)</description></item><item><title>Atomic Spectra</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AtomicSpectra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AtomicSpectra/</guid><description>Go Back
Differences in Discrete Energy Levels Key Points:
Unique Spectra: As the discrete energy levels for atoms are fixed and unique to each atom, the discrete energy level differences are also fixed and unique to each element.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Structure</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AtomicStructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/AtomicStructure/</guid><description>Go Back
John Dalton 1803-08: Proposed “Atomic Theory of Matter“
Matter (elements) is composed of small, indivisible, particles called “atoms” All atoms for a given element are identical (same shape, size, mass, chemical properties) Atoms are not created, destroyed or changed into different types in a chemical reaction: a chemical reaction involves the rearrangement, combination or separation of atoms Atoms combine in fixed proportions to form compounds Atom is a sphere Disadvantages</description></item><item><title>Chromatography</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Chromatography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Chromatography/</guid><description>go back
Series of analytical techniques that can be used to separate mixtures of compounds for further use or for analysis In all forms of chromatography, a mobile phase moves through or across a stationary phase Stationary phase: This phase does not move.</description></item><item><title>Close Reading Structure</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/CloseReading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/CloseReading/</guid><description>go back
A way of interpreting a text&amp;rsquo;s main meaning/message You do not need a conclusion for this, but can include one if you wish Introduction Short introduction(not like an essay) What is the text about?</description></item><item><title>Closed and Open Pipes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/ClosedAndOpenPipes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/ClosedAndOpenPipes/</guid><description>go back
Vibrations Vibration: Mechanical phenomenon where oscillation occurs around an equilibrium point Free Vibration: When a force is applied to any object, then that object is allowed to vibrate at its natural frequency Forced Vibration: When a force is applied to an object and it is forced to vibrate at a particular frequency Natural frequency: frequency at which an object vibrates when it is not disturbed by an outside force Resonance Resonance: Phenomenon that occurs where an object is forced to vibrate at its natural frequency Energy is transferred from the forced oscillator to the receiver with maximum efficiency, and the amplitude of the vibration is increased greatly Modes of Vibration The different ways in which a system vibrates naturally/oscillates The frequency of oscillation is termed as modal frequency.</description></item><item><title>Concentration</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Concentration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Concentration/</guid><description>go back
Concentration refers to the amount of solute dissolve in the solvent. We can use many kinds of units to describe how much solute we have in a solvent.</description></item><item><title>Covalent Bonding</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/covalent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/covalent/</guid><description>go back
Electrostatic force of attraction between shared pair of electrons and the nuclei on either side Non-metal atoms involved Covalent bonding: Non-metal atoms share one or more pairs of electrons by overlapping valence shells to give each a nobel gas structure A covalent bond is a shared pair of electrons There is a force of attraction between the bonding pair of electrons and the nuclei of the atoms at each side Hydrogen atoms only need 2 electrons in their outer level to reach the noble gas structure of helium Octet Rule: Atoms gain, lose or share eelectrons when they combine with other atoms to acquire a stable octet (8) of electrons There are exceptions: $SF_6$ and $BCl_3$ Properties Non-conductors of electricity Electrons are localised in the electron cloud or as bonding pairs Therefore, they are immobile, and cannot conduct charge Bad conductors of heat No free particles that can move from one end of the particle to another, carrying kinetic energy (temperature) Thus, it is a bad conductor of heat Soft Only weak intermolecular forces exist between the molecules and so these molecules can be easily separated and rearranged when a force is applied, making them soft Low melting/boiling point Only weak intermolecular forces exist between the molecules Small amount of energy is need to overcome these bonds, and there is a low melting/boiling point These increase with molecular size, which increases the strength of the bonds Note: These are for Covalent Molecular Structures, not Covalent Network Structures, which you do not need to know .</description></item><item><title>Crude Oil</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/CrudeOil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/CrudeOil/</guid><description> go back
Coal and Crude Oil Formation Fractional Distillation A method of separating fractions of crude oil Crude oil: all unprocessed oil, a mixture of hydrocarbons with different chain lengths Fractions: a group of hydrocarbons with a similar length chain The longer the molecule, the greater the intermolecular forces, therefore the greater amount of energy required to break the bonds Crude oil fractions Refined gas Petrol Naphtha Wax Bitumen Steps Crude oil is heated in a furnace The heated crude oil, mostly in a vapour state, is pumped into the column and travels very fast due to its energy The column has a heat gradient, and decreases in temperature going up, with the very bottom being very hot The constituents that have higher boiling points will collect at lower points and condense, while substances with lower boiling points will rise higher and condense at higher points due to the higher areas being cooler (increasing boiling points) Gas Petrol Naphtha Kerosene Diesel Bitumen Shorter chain molecules have lower boiling points and will therefore reach the higher area The condensations are collected</description></item><item><title>Definitions</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Definitions/</guid><description>go back
Viscosity: thickness of fluid, how resistant a fluid is to movement through it Volatility: a measure of how readily a substance vaporises or transitions from a liquid phase to a gas phase Melting point: temperature at which matter changes from solid to liquid form Boiling point: temperature at which matter changes from liquid to gas form Fossil: preserved remains or traces of a living thing Fossil fuel: Substances that were formed from decaying animal and plant matter being submitted to high temperatures and pressure over millions of years.</description></item><item><title>Definitions</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/Definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/Definitions/</guid><description>go back
Decay: occurs when unstable nuclei breakdown into smaller parts, sitting small particles with high energy
Radioactive decay: process in which unstable nuclei break down into smaller particles</description></item><item><title>Diffraction</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Diffraction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Diffraction/</guid><description> The bending/deformation of wave fronts as they pass through a gap or around an obstacle $\lambda &amp;gt;= d$ , where d is the distance of the gap</description></item><item><title>Dosimetry</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Dosimetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Dosimetry/</guid><description> When our cells are exposed to ionising radiation, this turns them into free radicals</description></item><item><title>Economic Growth</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/EconomicGrowth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/EconomicGrowth/</guid><description>go back
Measures of Economic Activity There are 3 ways to measure the value of aggregate output, suggested by the circular flow of income model, all giving rise to the same result Expenditure approach: Adds up all spending to buy final goods and services produced within a country over a time period $C+I+G+(X-M)$ Income approach: Adds up all income earned by the factors of production that reduce all goods and services within a country over a time period Output approach: calculates the value of all final goods and services produced in a country over a time period National Income National income: measures the monetary value of the flow of output of goods and services produced in an economy over a period of time You will not have to define this Main function of National Income Accounting is to provide data to analyse the overall performance of the economy Can be calculated in the 3 ways mentioned above Economics Growth Increasing capacity of an economy to satisfy the material wants of the population Growth is generally thought to be the most important macroeconomic objective because it determines the future opportunity set of the economy and enables households to achieve a higher standard of living in material terms Has 2 meanings Growth refers to an increase in the output that an economy produces over a period of time (actual growth) Growth also refers to an increase in what an economy can produce if it is using all its scarce resources (potential growth) An increase in potential growth can be shown by an outward shift in the PPF curve Gross Domestic Product The most frequency use measure of economic performance is the Gross Domestic Product (GDP) Defined as the total market value of all final goods and services produced in a country over a given period of time(usually over a year) GDP does not measure PPF of an economy GDP numbers are of little importance in themselves Economists place importance on the rate of change in GDP (the rate of economic growth) Rate of growth: Percentage change in GDP growth Nominal GDP vs Real GDP Real GDP: Measures the money value of all goods and services produces within the territory adjusted for price changes</description></item><item><title>Electronic Configuration</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/ElectronicConfig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/ElectronicConfig/</guid><description>go back
Electrons are arranged in energy levels or shells
n is the principal quantum number or shell number</description></item><item><title>Energy</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Energy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Energy/</guid><description>go back
Energy Energy: capacity to do work Work: exertion of force overcoming resistance or producing molecular change Exothermic reaction gives out heat Endothermic reaction absorbs heat Direct + Indirect uses of Energy Direct</description></item><item><title>Exam Information</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/ExamInformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/ExamInformation/</guid><description>Practice Questions Explain how your understanding of a studies text&amp;rsquo;s social and cultural context has enriched your interpretation of it</description></item><item><title>Exam Quotes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/ExamQuotesSem1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/ExamQuotesSem1/</guid><description>go back
The Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde Core Concept: Value of reputation
People will do anything to make them like them</description></item><item><title>Fission and Fusion</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/FissionFusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/FissionFusion/</guid><description> go back
Nuclear Fission Nucleus of an atom is bombarded with neutrons to split the heavier nucleus into smaller and lighter nuclei This makes the nucleus so unstable that it splits into 2 A lot of energy is released Occur artificially Little energy is required to split an atom Atomic bomb is based on concept of nuclear fission Often involves releases of gamma rays and free neutrons $$^1_0n+ ^{235}{92}U-&amp;gt;^{141}{56}Ba+^{92}_{36}Kr+3 ^1_0 n$$ Nuclear Fusion 2 or more lighter nuclei combine to form a heavier nucleus An enormous amount of energy is released, much larger than nuclear fission Occurs in stars and the sun Huge amount of energy is required to bring 2 atoms together Therefore, happens in very, very hot conditions Cold fusion is a concept that entails nuclear fusion happening at room temperature Hydrogen bomb is based on concept of nuclear fusion Usually releases neutrons or protons as well as new nucleus Strong magnetic field is required for magnetic confinement Ensures plasma doesn’t escape Confinement ensures that fusion occurs, and makes it safe</description></item><item><title>Force and Free Body Diagrams</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Force/</guid><description>go back
Force: Mass (kg) x acceleration ($ms^{-2}$), units in Newtons (N)
Vector Quantity, include direction $$ f=ma $$</description></item><item><title>Geometric Proofs</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/GeometricProofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/GeometricProofs/</guid><description>Things you are assumed to know already Angle sum theorems for triangles and quadrilaterals Properties of intersecting lines Congruence of vertically opposite angles Relationships involving angles in parallel lines with a transversal Corresponding, alternate, interior Isosceles angle theorem Angles opposite to the equal sides of an isosceles triangle are also equal.</description></item><item><title>Gothic Literature</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Goth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Goth/</guid><description>go back
The Dark Ages Alternatively the Middle Ages (approx. 800 AD - 1500) A time of “intellectual darkness” Feudal societies resign many citizens to the uneducated peasantry Artistic and cultural developments of Antiquity perceived to have halted Emphasis on logic and reason gives way to increased reliance on dogmatic systems of belief Church of England Superstitions or folk beliefs Also historically associated with violence, depravity “Gothic” becomes a bad word</description></item><item><title>Half Life</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/HalfLife/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/HalfLife/</guid><description>go back
The time it takes for $1/2$ of a sample of a given radionuclide to undergo decay Ways of measuring Number of nuclides (nuclides/time) Mass of radioisotopes $$N_1=N_0 \times (\frac{1}{2})^x$$</description></item><item><title>How to Study for Year 11 Literature</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Study/</guid><description>You should be doing at least 2 hours study per week for Lit in Year 11. Listed below are some of the things you should be doing in that time.</description></item><item><title>Hydrocarbons</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Hydrocarbons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Chemistry/Hydrocarbons/</guid><description>go back
Hydrocarbons Functional Groups and Homologous Series Functional group: atom or group of atoms responsible for the typical chemical reactions of a molecule Homologous series is a group of molecules with the same functional group but a different number of -CH2 groups Family that differs by number of carbon atoms Functional groups determine the pattern of reactivity of a homologous series, whereas the carbon chain length determines physical properties such as melting/boiling points Carbon Bonding capacity: 4 Can form 4 covalent bonds 4 valence electrons Sharing 1 electron forms a covalent bond Carbon can make double or triple covalent bonds Saturated Hydrocarbons Hydrocarbons with only single bonds between carbon atoms Simplest class of hydrocarbons Each carbon atom is bonded to as many hydrogen atoms as possible Makes them relatively unreactive/un-volatile, apart from their interaction with the oxygen in the air in the case of combustion Structural Isomers Isomers: organic molecules with the same molecular formula but a different structural formula Structural isomers have: Different names Different shapes Different chemical properties Read from left to right for isomers Alkanes Family of hydrocarbons Saturated hydrocarbons with only single bonds between the carbon atoms Can be arranged in continuous straight chains or in branches or rings Hydrogen = 2 x carbon + 2 Naming Alkanes: Branched Find the parent chain = longest continuous chain of carbon atoms in the molecule Number the carbon atoms in the parent chain.</description></item><item><title>I'm free</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/28-06-2023-im-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/NotTheTagArticles/28-06-2023-im-free/</guid><description>go back
I&amp;rsquo;m finally free.
The group&amp;rsquo;s split up, which is kinda sad.
But now I don&amp;rsquo;t have false friends.</description></item><item><title>Ibsen and Hedda Gabler</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/HeddaGabler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/HeddaGabler/</guid><description>Henrik Ibsen Born March 20, 1826 in Skien, Norway Died May 23 1906 Considered the most influential playwright of his time, the late 19th century One of the founders of modernism in theatre and is often referred to as &amp;ldquo;the father of realism&amp;rdquo; Author of Hedda Gabler Introduced to the European stage a new order of moral analysis Left a lasting legacy - his works continue to resonate strongly today as they tap into universal themes and explore the human condition in unique ways Author James Joyce once wrote that Ibsen &amp;ldquo;has provoked more discussion and criticism than that of any other living man&amp;rdquo; Hedda Gabler - 1891 or 1890?</description></item><item><title>Important Variables to Know</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Variable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Variable/</guid><description>go back
Vectors (require direction and magnitude) s: Displacement
in meters v: Velocity $ms^{-1}$, meters per second F: force Newtons J: work Joules i: Impulse $kg\ ms^{-1}$, kg per meters per second W: watts p: Momentum $kg\ ms^{-1}$, kg per meters per second N: Newtons a: Acceleration $ms^{-2}$, meters per, seconds squared g: Gravity, 9.</description></item><item><title>Intermolecular Forces</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/IntermolecularForces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/IntermolecularForces/</guid><description>go back
Forces between molecules Allotropes: Different physical forms of the same element E.g., carbon, diamond, graphite Gases: Very weak attraction between particles Liquid: stronger attraction between particles Solids: Very strong attraction between particles Also known as Van Der Waal&amp;rsquo;s forces Dispersion Forces Forces existing between 2 polar or non-polar molecules Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between 2 oppositely charged temporary/induced dipoles Electrons move randomly; thus dipoles are temporary, as their charges is based on these electrons, as their localisation is temporary Molecules with dipoles can polarise other molecules and make them form temporary dipoles - these are called induced dipoles This ESF of attraction between the temporary and induced dipoles are known as dispersion forces These are temporary, as electrons move randomly, therefore the dipoles form, break apart, and reform randomly Ion-dipole Forces Forces existing between an ion and a polar molecule Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between an ion and a dipole Note: &amp;ldquo;Intermolecular force&amp;rdquo; is a misnomer, as this is in ionic substances, not covalent substances Stronger than permanent dipole-dipole and dispersion forces Permanent Dipole-Dipole Forces present between 2 polar molecules Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between 2 net dipoles; i.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Economics</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Introduction2Economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Introduction2Economics/</guid><description>Go back
Macro-economics vs Micro-economics Macro-economics and Micro-economics are 2 of the largest subdivisions of the study of economics Micro- refers to the observation of small economics units Effects of government regulations on individual markets and consumer decision making Macro- refers to the “big picture” version of economics How interest rates are determined Why some economics grow faster than others Micro-economics Individual markets Consumers Producers/firrms Government How their actions influence decisions and individual markets Utility maximisation/satisfaction Firm production and profit maximisation Individual market equilibrium Effects of government regulations on individual markets Externalities and other side effects Macro-economics The big picture Focuses on aggregate production and consumption in an economy Effects of general taxes such as income and sales taxes on output and prices Causes of economics upswings and downturns Effects of monetary and fiscal policies on economics health Effects of, and process for, determining interest rates Causes for some economies growing faster than other economies Uses GDP (Gross Domestic Product: monetary value of all finished goods and services within a give time period) and goods and services by their market price Inflation, unemployment rate, GDP Scarcity We have unlimited wants and limited resources to satisfy those wwants There is a scarcity of resources Resources have alternative uses Basic Economic Problem (BEP) BEP is every and affects us all Due to the problem of “relative scarcity” Scarcity relative to our wants Resources may be abundant but wants are unlimited, how are the resources allocated: relative scarcity Due to scarcity, we are forced to make choices Resources cannot be used for all human wants We must choose We have unlimited wants, but there is a scarcity of resources to satisfy those wants.</description></item><item><title>Ionic Bonding</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/ionic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/ionic/</guid><description>go back
Electrostatic force of attraction between oppositely charged(cations and anions) ions in a network
Consists of a metal and a non-metal combined together</description></item><item><title>Linear Equations</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Lines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Lines/</guid><description>go back
The equation for a straight line is $$y=mx+c$$
y and x are values on the graph</description></item><item><title>Market Efficiency</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarketEfficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarketEfficiency/</guid><description>go back
Consumer Surplus: Highest price consumers are willing to pay for a good minus the price actually paid</description></item><item><title>Market Equilibrium and Price Determination</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarPri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarPri/</guid><description>go back
Market Equilibrium: State of a market that has no tendency to change Equilibrium Price: Price a which $Q_{supplied}=Q_{demanded}$ There is no surplus or shortage in a market equilibrium There is no pressure to change price The market clears, i.</description></item><item><title>Market Failure - Externalities</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/externalities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/externalities/</guid><description>go back
Occurs when the actions of consumers or producers give rise to negative or positive side effects on others who are not part of these actions, and whose interests are not taken into consideration People (not involved in the economic transaction) feeling the effects of an externality are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;third parties&amp;rdquo; If these side-effects (spillovers) on third parties involve benefits, there arises a positive externality, also known as external benefit If they involve costs in the form of side-effects (spillovers), there arises a negative externality, also known as external costs Externalities can arise from either consumption activities (consumption externalities) or producer activities (producer externalities) There are 4 types of externalities Negative Production Externalities Negative Consumption Externalities Positive Production Externalities Positive Consumption Externalities Marginal External Cost (MEC): Additional cost incurred by third parties who are not involved in the consumption and production of additional unit of the good Marginal Social Cost (MSC): MPC + MEC; Additional costs incurred by society&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Market Failure - Free and Public Goods</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/freeandpublicgoods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/freeandpublicgoods/</guid><description>#marketfailure
go back
We learned that in a free competitive market, when the price of a good adjusts to make quantity demanded equal to quantity supplied, the equilibrium quantity reflects the &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; or optimal allocation of resources to the production of that good</description></item><item><title>Market Failure - Policies</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/policies/</guid><description>go back
#marketfailure
Negative Externalities of Production Government regulations Rely on &amp;ldquo;command&amp;rdquo; approach, using authority to enact legislation and regulations in the public&amp;rsquo;s interest Regulations can be used to prevent or reduce the effects of production externalities In the case of the polluting firm, regulations can forbid the dumping of certain toxic substances into the environment More commonly, regulations do not totally ban the production of pollutants, but rather attempt to achieve one of the following Limit the emission of pollutants by setting a maximum limit of pollutants permitted Limit the quantity of output produced by the producer Require polluting firms to install technologies reducing the emissions The impact is to lower the quantity of the good produced and bring it to the optimal supply curve by shifting MPC up to MSC Pollutant and output restrictions achieve this by forcing the firm to produce less.</description></item><item><title>Market Failure in Gas and Oil Market</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Investigation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Investigation/</guid><description>go back
Australia’s Oil Industry Australia produced 334.737 barrels of oil a day in Dec 2021, and the oil and gas industry has continued to grow with 24.</description></item><item><title>Market Power</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarketPower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/MarketPower/</guid><description>#marketfailure
go back
Market power is the ability of a business to insulate itself from competition It also refers to the ability of a firm (or group of firms) to raise and maintain price above the level that would prevail under competition; this is referred to as market or monopoly power The exercise of market power leads to reduced output and loss of economic welfare Competitive Market Competition is generally understood to be a process in which rivals compete in order to achieve some objective.</description></item><item><title>Mass Defect</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/MassDefect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/MassDefect/</guid><description> go back
Mass defect The total mass of a stable nucleus is always less than the combined masses of the nucleons Mass defect: difference between total mass of the individual nucleons, and the mass of the nucleus as a whole  The difference in mass is considered to be the binding energy of the nucleus Binding Energy The difference in mass (mass defect) is considered to be binding energy If the mass of 4He was equal to the mass of 2 protons + 2 neutrons, the nucleus would fall apart without any input of energy To be stable, its mass must be less than that of its constituents combined  The nuclear binding energy represents the amount of energy that must be put into a nucleus to break it apart into its individual nucleons Equations SI units We can calculate the energy through $e=mc^2$ e = energy in J m = mass in kg c = speed of light, or 300 000 000 m/s Other units Sometimes, you&amp;rsquo;ll be given units in amu In this case, find the mass of all nucleons, and subtract the mass of the nucleus from that You should get a value in amu Multiply this by 931, and this will be the binding energy in MeV This can be converted into Joules using the data sheet formulas In short: $MeV = 931\times amu$</description></item><item><title>Mass Spectrometry</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/MassSpectrometry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/MassSpectrometry/</guid><description>go back
Relative Atomic Mass In this context: weighted average of all isotopes occurring naturally of an element, relative to $\frac{1}{12}$ of the mass of a Carbon-12 atom in its ground state We use this when determining composition of elements from mass spectrometry Determined from mass spectrums Calculated as $$Ar(X)=\frac{(% a \times m(A))+(% b \times m(B))&amp;hellip;(% z \times m(Z))}{100}$$ Where $%a$ is percentage abundance of isotope A.</description></item><item><title>Matrices</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/Matrices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/Matrices/</guid><description>Matrices are a way of graphically storing certain data. $$\begin{bmatrix}
x \
y
\end{bmatrix}$$
Matrix Addition $$\begin{bmatrix}
a &amp;amp; b \</description></item><item><title>Metallic Bonding</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/metal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/metal/</guid><description>Electrostatic forces of attraction between cations of metal and a sea of delocalised electrons
Metal atoms are packed together in a giant metallic lattice</description></item><item><title>Metaphysical Poetry</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Literature/MetaphysicalPoetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Literature/MetaphysicalPoetry/</guid><description>go back
Context: Renaissance Period
Classical art/subjects, e.g. romance, sonnets, poetry 17th Century England Church Believed in Christianity Elizabethan Poetry,Shakespeare Metaphysical language Meta: Greek for beyond Physics: physical nature BEYOND physical nature E.</description></item><item><title>Methods of Separation</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/MethodsOfSeparation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/MethodsOfSeparation/</guid><description>go back
Separating Mixtures Mixtures can be separated by any means that makes use of the different physical properties of its constituents.</description></item><item><title>Mixtures</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Mixtures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Mixtures/</guid><description>go back
Atom: Smallest unit of matter that cannot be chemically divided Element: Substance that cannot be decomposed further by a chemical reaction.</description></item><item><title>Momentum and Impulse</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Momentum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Momentum/</guid><description>go back
Momentum Momentum: Mass (kg) x Velocity (m/s) , units are $kg$ $ms^{-1}$
Vector quantity, include direction $$ p = mv $$</description></item><item><title>Motion Equations</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Motion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Motion/</guid><description>go back
SUVAT Equations S: Displacement: m
U: Initial Velocity: $ms^{-1}$
V: Final Velocity: $ms^{-1}$
A: Acceleration: $ms^{-2}$
T: Time: s</description></item><item><title>Nano-materials</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Nanomaterials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Nanomaterials/</guid><description>go back
Most of these are mine, but I have stolen adapted some of Ajay&amp;rsquo;s notes. I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna tell you, you can guess.</description></item><item><title>Narrative Conventions and Language Devices</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Conventions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Conventions/</guid><description>go back
Narrative conventions: Characterisation (SAAO)
Setting (physical, context)
Point of View
1st person I, me 2nd person You, we, us E.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Fission and Fusion</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearFissionAndFusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearFissionAndFusion/</guid><description> go back
Nuclear Fission Nucleus of an atom is bombarded with neutrons to split the heavier nucleus into smaller and lighter nuclei This makes the nucleus so unstable that it splits into 2 A lot of energy is released Occur artificially Little energy is required to split an atom Atomic bomb is based on concept of nuclear fission Often involves releases of gamma rays and free neutrons $$^1_0n+ ^{235}{92}U-&amp;gt;^{141}{56}Ba+^{92}_{36}Kr+3 ^1_0 n$$ Nuclear Fusion 2 or more lighter nuclei combine to form a heavier nucleus An enormous amount of energy is released, much larger than nuclear fission Occurs in stars and the sun Huge amount of energy is required to bring 2 atoms together Therefore, happens in very, very hot conditions Cold fusion is a concept that entails nuclear fusion happening at room temperature Hydrogen bomb is based on concept of nuclear fusion Usually releases neutrons or protons as well as new nucleus Strong magnetic field is required for magnetic confinement Ensures plasma doesn’t escape Confinement ensures that fusion occurs, and makes it safe Mass defect The total mass of a stable nucleus is always less than the combined masses of the nucleons Mass defect: difference between total mass of the individual nucleons, and the mass of the nucleus as a whole  The difference in mass is considered to be the binding energy of the nucleus We can calculate the energy through $e=mc^2$ e = energy in J m = mass in kg c = speed of light, or 300 000 000 m/s Binding Energy The difference in mass (mass defect) is considered to be binding energy If the mass of 4He was equal to the mass of 2 protons + 2 neutrons, the nucleus would fall apart without any input of energy To be stable, its mass must be less than that of its constituents combined  The nuclear binding energy represents the amount of energy that must be put into a nucleus to break it apart into its individual nucleons Nuclear Energy Element is bombarded with neutrons Neutrons are absorbed Nucleus becomes unstable and splits into smaller nuclei, radioactive energy and lone neutrons</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Physics</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearPhysics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearPhysics/</guid><description>go back
Atoms Central part of an atom is the nucleus Consists of: Neutrons No charge: 0 Relative Atomic Mass: 1 Protons Positive Charge + Relative Atomic Mass: 1 Collectively called nucleons Almost identical in mass and size Most of an atom is empty space that is only occupied by electrons Any change in the amount of protons changes the element  Electrons Negative Charge: - Relative Atomic Mass: 1/1836 Orbit nucleus at high speeds $$^A_ZX$$ A: Mass number No.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Physics</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Nuclear-Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Nuclear-Physics/</guid><description>go back
Name Symbol Relative Mass Absolute Mass Relative charge Absolute charge Location Protons P 1 $1.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Physics as a Human Endeavour</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearPhysicsHumanEndeavours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Physics/NuclearPhysicsHumanEndeavours/</guid><description>go back
Nuclear Power Stations Pros Energy efficient Small land footprint Average nuclear power plant producing 2000 MW takes up a square mile of space Very powerful, energy wise Reliable Produce their maximum power output 93% of the time Very stable Produces no greenhouse gases Cons Closely connected to nuclear weapon technology production/proliferation Dangerous to society Nuclear waste Extremely poisonous products Takes 10s of 1000s of years to stop being radioactive/poisonous Possibility of nuclear accidents Uncontrolled nuclear chain reactions Neutrons from fission reaction create another fission reaction Causes excess of energy in the form of heat Sometimes the heat is too much for the reactor to handle It melts, and radioactive waste is expelled Expensive to set up Uranium is expensive Nuclear Power Station Components Fuel rods: long, thin rods containing pellets of enriched uranium Moderator: material that slows down neutrons Graphite, water, heavy water, carbon dioxide Heavy water is the best but is too expensive Water with dueterium, (Hydrogen-2) an isotope of hydrogen Graphite and carbon dioxide contain carbon which is denser than hydrogen Ensures that neutron capture occurs When the neutrons collide with small nuclei, they lose most of their kinetic energy Control rods: material that absorbs neutrons Boron steel or cadmium Ensures energy release is controlled and stable, due to them controlling the amount of neutrons for fission Coolant: liquid to absorb heat energy that has been produced by nuclear fission, goes to cooling tower to cool down e.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Physics In Real Life</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/nuclearphysicsinreallife/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/nuclearphysicsinreallife/</guid><description>go back
Nuclear Power Stations Pros Energy efficient Small land footprint Average nuclear power plant producing 2000 MW takes up a square mile of space Very powerful, energy wise Reliable Produce their maximum power output 93% of the time Very stable Produces no greenhouse gases Cons Closely connected to nuclear weapon technology production/proliferation Dangerous to society Nuclear waste Extremely poisonous products Takes 10s of 1000s of years to stop being radioactive/poisonous Possibility of nuclear accidents Uncontrolled nuclear chain reactions Neutrons from fission reaction create another fission reaction Causes excess of energy in the form of heat Sometimes the heat is too much for the reactor to handle It melts, and radioactive waste is expelled Expensive to set up Uranium is expensive Nuclear Power Station Components Fuel rods: long, thin rods containing pellets of enriched uranium Moderator: material that slows down neutrons Graphite, water, heavy water, carbon dioxide Heavy water is the best but is too expensive Water with dueterium, (Hydrogen-2) an isotope of hydrogen Graphite and carbon dioxide contain carbon which is denser than hydrogen Ensures that neutron capture occurs When the neutrons collide with small nuclei, they lose most of their kinetic energy Control rods: material that absorbs neutrons Boron steel or cadmium Ensures energy release is controlled and stable, due to them controlling the amount of neutrons for fission Coolant: liquid to absorb heat energy that has been produced by nuclear fission, goes to cooling tower to cool down e.</description></item><item><title>Pathogens</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Biology/Pathogens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Biology/Pathogens/</guid><description>go back
Microorganisms that cause Disease Bacteria Majority of bacteria are non-pathogenic (harmless to humans) Some are pathogenic (cause disease) Essential to life on Earth Decomposition of organic material and cycling of elements In/on the human body, bacteria colonise the gut, mouth, skin, genitals and airways Single-celled microscopic (0.</description></item><item><title>Patterns/Trends in the Periodic Table</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Patterns/</guid><description>Go Back
Reactivity of Group 1 Metals increases as there are more valence electron shells
ESF: Electrostatic Forces of Attraction</description></item><item><title>Periodicity</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Periodicity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Periodicity/</guid><description> go back
Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure what this is about.
Update 13/4/2023: I have been told that it&amp;rsquo;s basically the same as periodic trends Update 15/4/2023: I have no idea what this is for Physical Properties Boiling point Melting point Hardness Conductivity Brittle Malleable Ductile Allotropes of Carbon Carbon has 4 valence electrons Can bond to itself, and forms a variety of different compounds Diamond Non-conductive of electricity High melting/boiling point Graphite 2D hexagonal layers Mobile delocalised electrons that are free to move within layers Dispersion forces between layers Conductive of electricity Buckyball - (Buckminster fulleren z ) Not conductive of electricity Used as a dry lubricant</description></item><item><title>Permutations and Combinations</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/PerCom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/PerCom/</guid><description>Permutations n! is equal to $n\times(n-1)\times(n-2)\times(n-3)&amp;hellip;\times2\times1$ When order is important Think of it as arranging items Notation is $^nP_r$ Where we are arranging r objects from n objects This equation can be written as: $$ \frac{n!</description></item><item><title>Permutations and Combinations</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/PerCom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/PerCom/</guid><description>Permutations n! is equal to $n\times(n-1)\times(n-2)\times(n-3)&amp;hellip;\times2\times1$ When order is important Think of it as arranging items Notation is $^nP_r$ Where we are arranging r objects from n objects This equation can be written as: $$ \frac{n!</description></item><item><title>pH Calculations.md</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/pHCalculations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/pHCalculations/</guid><description>$$pH=-log_{10}(H^+)$$
$$H^+ = 10^{-pH}$$</description></item><item><title>Physics as a Human Endeavor</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/humanstuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/humanstuff/</guid><description>go back
Car Safety Holding the mass of the car and the total change in velocity constant (as when braking you will always be breaking from a set speed), the impulse for the car will be constant as well, because $I=m\Delta v$ When a car breaks suddenly, as the non-seat-belt-wearing passengers have a tendency to maintain their path (inertia), they are flung forward until they collide with the front; at this point, a force acts on them to slow them down along with the car Crumple Zones When 2 cars collide, the crumple zone contracts (absorbing the impact force) and thus a retarding force is applied on the car through a larger amount of time.</description></item><item><title>Polarity</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Polarity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/Polarity/</guid><description>go back
Electronegativity is the ability of an atom in gaseous phase to attract electrons to itself Bond Polarity The property of shared pairs of electrons being closer to one atom than the other in a covalent bond results in an uneven distribution of electrical charge along the bond.</description></item><item><title>Potable Water</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/PotableWater/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/PotableWater/</guid><description>go back
On average, water makes up approx. 55-78% of a person&amp;rsquo;s body mass Differs with sex, age, body weight, etc Essential for our body E.</description></item><item><title>Price Elasticity of Demand (PED)</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/PED/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/PED/</guid><description>go back
Measures the responsiveness of quantity demanded of a good to a change in its price, ceteris paribus Depends on what %Δ you want, use price for price, and QD for QD Elasticity declines along demand curve as we move towards quantity axis Elasticities When price elasticity is between $0$ and $-1$, demand is price inelastic* When price elasticity is between $-1$ and $- ∞$, demand is price elastic When price elasticity is $-1$, demand is unit price elastic When DD is price elastic, the slope of the DD curve is gentler When DD is price inelastic, the slope of the DD curve is steeper Price Elastic:** Price change results in a more than proportionate change in quantity demanded Price Inelastic:** Price change results in a less than proportionate change in quantity demanded Unit Price Elastic: Price change results in a proportionate change in quantity demanded Factors that Affect PED for a Good Number and closeness of substitutes in the same price range Time period Proportion of income consumers spend on a good Degree of necessity of the good to the consumers Habit of the consumer Number and Closeness of Substitutes in the Same Price Range The longer the number of substitutes (in the same price range), the higher the PED, and vice versa Time Period The longer the time period, the higher the PED More scope for the discovery of new substitutes More receptive to new products Availability of substitutes Proportion of Income Consumers Spend on a Good: Lower The lower the proportion of income spent on a good, the lower the PED Only a small proportion of income (won’t affect PED) If price increases, quantity demanded will decrease less than proportionately Less responsive to price changes, no incentive to look for substitutes Demand is price inelastic Proportion of Income Consumers Spend on a Good: Higher The higher the proportion of income spent on the good, the higher the PED Very large proportion of income If price increases, quantity demanded will decrease more than proportionately Very responsive to price changes Demand is price elastic Degree of Necessity of the Good to the Consumers: Higher The higher the degree of necessity, the lower the PED Essential to satisfy needs If price increases, quantity demanded will decreases less that proportionately Less responsive to price changes Demand is price inelastic Degree of Necessity of the Good to the Consumers: Lower The lower the degree of necessity, the higher the PED Luxury items are not essential to satisfy needs If price increases, quantity demanded will decrease more than proportionately Sensitive to price change Demand is price elastic Habit of the Consumer If the goods are consumed out of habit, an increase in price leads to a less than proportionate fall in quantity demanded Demand is price inelastic Total Revenue and PED Why is a knowledge of PED useful to firms?</description></item><item><title>Price Elasticity of Supply (PES)</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/PES/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/PES/</guid><description>go back
Measures responsiveness of quantity supplied of a good to a change in its price, ceteris paribus When a price change results in a more than proportionate change in quantity supplied, SS is price elastic When a price change results in a less than proportionate change in quantity supplied, SS is price inelastic When a price change results in a proportionate change in quantity supplied, SS is unit price elastic Price elastic: $1&amp;lt;PES&amp;lt;∞$ Price inelastic: $0&amp;lt;PES&amp;lt;1$ Unit Price Elastic:************************* $PES=1$ Any straight line starting from the origin is unit price elastic Factors Affecting PES Time Period Very short run Short run Long run Mobility of Factors of Production Spare capacity of firms Level of stocks and inventories Time Period Very Short Run*</description></item><item><title>Probability</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Probability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Probability/</guid><description>go back
A measure of the likelihood of an event occurring $P(A)$ is the probability of A occurring Theoretical Probability: theory probability, e.</description></item><item><title>Properties of Matter</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/PropertiesofMatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/PropertiesofMatter/</guid><description> go back
Mixtures Homogenous mixtures 2 or more particles are mixed together so well that you only see one thing Composition is uniform throughout Composition is spread evenly Pure Substance Only one kind of particle in it Heterogenous materials Composition is not spread evenly Homogenous Materials One set of properties No physical separation between particles Composition is spread evenly Solute: What is dissolved Solvent: What dissolves the solute Solutions Solute is equally distributed in solvent  Saturated solution Concentration of solute is at a maximum No more solute can dissolve Supersaturated Solution At a high temperature, solution appears saturated At lower temperatures, solute will precipitate out There is more solute in the solvent than can be dissolved Unsaturated solution Concentration of solute is below maximum More of the solute can dissolve</description></item><item><title>Quadratic Equations</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Quadratics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Quadratics/</guid><description> Quadratic equations are an equation of form $ax^2+bx+c=0$, where $a$, $b$, and $c$ are constants, and $a \neq 0$ You will be asked to solve these in 4 ways</description></item><item><title>Random Quotes from Edward</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/EdwardQuote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/EdwardQuote/</guid><description>go back
&amp;ldquo;For man is not truly one but truly two&amp;rdquo; - writing his essay on Jekyll and Hyde</description></item><item><title>Romanticism Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Rom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/Rom/</guid><description>go back
Ego-centric point of view Context Romanticism: attitude or intellectual orientation that characterised many works of literature, paintings, music, architecture and criticism in Western civilisation over a period from the late 18th century to the mid-19th century Can be seen as a rejection of the precepts of order, calm, harmony, balance, idealisation, and rationality that typified late 18th century Neo-classicism in particular Also a reaction against the Enlightenment and against 18th Century l The Romantic Movement Freedom of the individual Rejection of restricting social conventions and political rule Fight for rights of the common man Emphasis on emotions and the imagination over reason and logic Free spontaneous action over controlled calculated behaviour Valorisation of the wilderness The “noble savage” Savage meaning people from other, non-Euro places Revival of interest on folklore and legends Chivalry As an aesthetic philosophy, Romanticism engages with these key concepts:</description></item><item><title>Scalars and Vectors</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/ScaVec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/ScaVec/</guid><description>go back
Scalars Value only with magnitude Distance (s), in m Speed (|v| or v), in $ms^{-1}$ Time (t), in s $$ |v| = \frac{s}{t} $$</description></item><item><title>School Subjects</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Subjects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Subjects/</guid><description>Year 11 11Chemistry 11Physics 11Economics 11Literature 11Methods 11Specialist Year 10 10Physics 10Chemistry 10Literature 10Biology</description></item><item><title>Science Inquiry Skills</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/SIS/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/SIS/</guid><description>go back
Accuracy:**** How close your experimentally derived number is to the “true” or “real” quantity being measured
Precision:*** How the repeat values or a given trial are to each other, OR the fineness of the scale on the instrument being used to take measurements</description></item><item><title>Seismic Phenomena</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/SeismicPhenomena/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/SeismicPhenomena/</guid><description>go back
Wave that travels through the Earth or a planetary body The propagation velocity of a seismic wave depends on density and elasticity of the medium as well as the type of wave.</description></item><item><title>Sister Sites</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/townsites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/townsites/</guid><description>The Town:
Ed&amp;rsquo;s Obsidian Notes by Edward Huynh spicata.99000000.xyz by Spicata Shan-Mei&amp;rsquo;s Notes by Shan-Mei Year 11 Notes by Reaper Into the Shadow Garten by Anonymous the notes by notmario Jacaranda by Thomas Han The Chicken Pen by π-thagoras The Cookie Gulag by Jole 0 by Athu Sathe Mace&amp;rsquo;s Notes by Mace Chettiyaden Loren&amp;rsquo;s 2023 Notion by Loren Wilde Cringe Notes by Tom Qiu Baju&amp;rsquo;s by Ajay Bisnath</description></item><item><title>Solubility and Precipitation</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/SolubilityPrecipitation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/SolubilityPrecipitation/</guid><description>go back
Solute: Substance can be dissolved Residue: Substance that cannot be dissolved Ion-dipole forces Electrostatic force of attraction between an ion and a polar molecule Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between an ion and a dipole Note: &amp;ldquo;Intermolecular force&amp;rdquo; is a misnomer, as this is in ionic substances, not covalent substances Stronger than permanent dipole-dipole and dispersion forces Ion – dipole forces form between ions of an ionic compound and molecules of water.</description></item><item><title>Some Australian Gothic Composing Prompts</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/AusGothicPrompts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Literature/AusGothicPrompts/</guid><description>go back
[!example]- Replaced by another
The Prime Minister never seems to last long and often disappears through no discernible democratic process.</description></item><item><title>Some Helpful Websites/Resources</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/SomeHelpfulWebsitesResources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/SomeHelpfulWebsitesResources/</guid><description>These are just some websites that I found useful for revision, practice tests, and just for general study. Hope they help.</description></item><item><title>Static Electricity</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/StaticElectricity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/StaticElectricity/</guid><description>go back
2 types of charge: positive and negative
3 types of charge state
Positive positron, proton, alpha particle, cation Negative electron, anion Neutral Neutron, anti-neutrino An object of charge will produce an electric field around it</description></item><item><title>Superposition</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Superposition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Superposition/</guid><description>go back
Superposition occurs when 2 waves travelling in the same medium meet Their amplitudes combine algebraically to produce a resultant wave at that particular instant When the 2 waves superimpose, the resultant displacement of the particles is equal to the algebraic sum of the individual displacements of the original waves Constructive Interference 2 waves of equal frequency that are in phase interfere/superimpose Resultant wave has an amplitude greater than each of the individual waves Equal to the sum of the amplitudes of the individual waves Application: Amplified Speakers When 2 speakers are made to produce the same sound, the sound waves produced interfere with each other Thus, at certain places (anti-nodes), constructive interference occurs, and the sound is louder (amplitude increases) At nodes, destructive interference occurs, and the sound is quieter (amplitude decreases) Destructive Interference 2 waves of equal frequency that are not in phase meet and superimpose, crating a resultant wave that has amplitude lower than each of the individual waves Here the individual waves have positive and negative amplitudes, and so they combine to produce a wave of smaller amplitude Complete Destructive Interference 2 waves of equal frequency that are completely not in phase, i.</description></item><item><title>The Bulbapedia</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Bulbapedia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Bulbapedia/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;My question is why? Why have you done this? For what purpose?&amp;rdquo; - Nyasha Ncube</description></item><item><title>The Circular Flow of Income</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/CircularFlowofIncome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/CircularFlowofIncome/</guid><description>go back
Macroeconomic model that describes the flow of resources, goods and services, and income between the parts of the economy</description></item><item><title>The Pigeonhole Principle</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/PigeonholePrinciple/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/PigeonholePrinciple/</guid><description>go back
[!important] The Pidgeonhole Principle If $m$ items are placed in $n$ pigeonholes, where $m&amp;gt;n$, then at least one pigeonhole will contain more than one item</description></item><item><title>The Tacoz Treasures</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/tacoztreasure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/tacoztreasure/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Theory of Demand</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Demand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Demand/</guid><description>go back
Markets Where Buyers and Sellers meet in order to exchange money for goods They do not always meet in person Goods can be bought by consumers and sold by suppliers in online markets, e.</description></item><item><title>The Theory of Proof</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/TheTheoryofProof/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/TheTheoryofProof/</guid><description>Basically a mathematical way of proving a statement E.g., If a is even and b is even, prove that a+b is even We must use notation, and definitions Notation Set $\mathbb{R}$ Real Numbers, all rational and irrational numbers $\mathbb{Q}$ Rational numbers, all numbers that can be expressed as a fraction $\mathbb{Z}$ Integers, all whole numbers $\mathbb{N}$ All natural numbers, i.</description></item><item><title>The Theory of Supply</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Supply/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Economics/Supply/</guid><description>go back
Amount of a good or service a producer is willing and able to sell in a given period of time, at a given price, ceteris paribus Objective of producers is to maximise profits $Profit = Revenue-Costs$ Law of Supply: In a given time period, the quantity supplied of a good or service is directly related to its price, ceteris paribus Produces aim to maximise profit, while consumers aim to maximise satisfaction Individual Supply: Refers to the sum of the individual supply for a good or service by all the producers in the market Market Supply: Refers to the sum of all the individual supply for a good or service by all the producers in the market Exceptional Supply Curves Vertical supply curve No matter the price, the same quantity is supplied E.</description></item><item><title>Town Analogy</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/town/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/town/</guid><description>based off of Edward&amp;rsquo;s analogy. Read: I&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;adapted it
Welcome</description></item><item><title>Trigonometry</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Trigonometry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Methods/Trigonometry/</guid><description>Exact Values Radians
0˚ $\frac{π}{6}$ $\frac{π}{4}$ $\frac{π}{3}$ $\frac{π}{2}$ sin(θ) 0 $\frac{1}{2}$ $\frac{1}{\sqrt{2}}$ $\frac{\sqrt{3}}{2}$ 1 cos(θ) 1 $\frac{\sqrt{3}}{2}$ $\frac{1}{\sqrt{2}}$ $\frac{1}{2}$ 0 tan(θ) 0 $\frac{1}{\sqrt{3}}$ 1 $\sqrt{3}$ undefined Degrees</description></item><item><title>Ultrasound Imaging</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/UltrasoundImaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/UltrasoundImaging/</guid><description>go back
Ultrasound waves are longitudinal mechanical waves, with a frequency of between 1000 to 20000 Hz. This is above the human hearing range.</description></item><item><title>Vectors</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/Vectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Specialist/Vectors/</guid><description>[!info] Dr Pearce
Some of the images were from my teacher, Dr Pearce.
Value with Direction and Magnitude Vector Diagrams Vectors can be represented in a diagram Arrows are used to represent vector quantities Must be some vector on each side Must be resolved Adding Vectors For 2 Vectors A and B</description></item><item><title>VSEPR - Valence Shell Electron Repulsion Theory</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/VSEPR/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Chemistry/VSEPR/</guid><description>go back
VSEPR model can predict the structure of most molecules and polyatomic ions in which the central atom is a non-metal Also works for some structures in which the central atom is a metal VSEPR builds on Lewis Electron Dot Structures Lewis structures alone predict only connectivity while the Lewis structure and VSEPR together can predict the geometry of each atom in a molecule Key Concepts The 4 pairs of electrons around a central atom repel each other Pairs of electrons arrange themselves so they are as far apart as possible The repulsion between lone pairs is greater than the repulsion between bonding Bent&amp;rsquo;s angle is 104.</description></item><item><title>Waves</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Waves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/Waves/</guid><description>go back
Waves: The transfer of energy from one place to another without the net displacement of matter</description></item><item><title>Work, Force and Powewr</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/WorkForcePower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Physics/WorkForcePower/</guid><description>go back
Energy: Ability to do work Measured in Joules (J) Work: $Fs$ = $Nm$ $$ E_k=\frac{1}{2}mv^2 $$</description></item><item><title>Writings</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/Writings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/Writings/Writings/</guid><description>Philosophical writings and recounts of things in my life
Stories and Such Town Analogy
Random Quotes from Edward</description></item><item><title>Year 10 Biology Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Biology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Biology/</guid><description>go back
Pathogens</description></item><item><title>Year 10 Chemistry Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Chemistry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Chemistry/</guid><description>go back
Year 11 Chemistry
Organic Chemistry Energy
Crude Oil
Hydrocarbons
Definitions</description></item><item><title>Year 10 Literature Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Literature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Literature/</guid><description>go back
Year 11 Literature
Only Meta-physical poetry 💀
Metaphysical Poetry</description></item><item><title>Year 10 Physics Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/10Subjects/10Physics/</guid><description>go back
Year 11 Notes
Literally only nuclear physics. I only started taking online notes in year 10.</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Chemistry Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Chemistry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Chemistry/</guid><description>go back
Year 10 Chemistry
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Economics Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Economics/</guid><description>go back
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Literature Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Literature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Literature/</guid><description>go back
Year 10 Literature
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Methods Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Methods/</guid><description>go back
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Physics Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Physics/</guid><description>go back
Year 10 Notes
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Year 11 Specialist Notes</title><link>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Specialist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://littleroot.toomwn.xyz/11Subjects/11Specialist/</guid><description>go back
THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item></channel></rss>