<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes Dump on</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/</link><description>Recent content in Notes Dump on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Definitions/</guid><description>Orbitals: Area of space that is likely to contain electrons
Cathode Ray Tube: A high vacuum tube in which cathode rays produce luminous images on a fluorescent screen</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/AboutMe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/AboutMe/</guid><description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m supaqwerty. I made this website as a side project.</description></item><item><title>Application of Demand and Supply - Price Controls</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/pricecontrols/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/pricecontrols/</guid><description>Price Floor Minimum price (lower price limit) allowed by legislation Government believes equilibrium price is too low Prices of all affected goods or services transacted cannot be below the minimum price allowed For a price floor to be effective, the legislated price, $P_{min}$, must be above the market equilibrium price Surplus occurs, as $Q_{supplied}&amp;gt;Q_{demanded}$ Quantity transacted will fall Consumer surplus will fall With government intervention, producers can earn more A minimum wage may help reduce the income gap between higher and lower wage earners Price Ceiling Opposite of a price floor Maximum price (upper price limit) allowed by legislation Prices of all affected goods or services transacted cannot be above the maximum price allowed For a price ceiling to be effective, the legislated price P_{max} must be below the equilibrium price What alternative means of resource allocation can replace the price mechanism, now that a price ceiling is imposed?</description></item><item><title>Application of Demand and Supply - Taxes and Subsidies</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/taxesandsubsidies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/taxesandsubsidies/</guid><description>Go back
Types of Tax Direct tax Income/wealth tax Paid by households or firms directly to the government Personal income tax Corporate tax Indirect tax Tax on Goods/Services Paid indirectly to the government via the sellers of the good Taxed on profit, not revenue Specific tax Ad valorem tax Example is General Sales Tax (GST) Indirect Tax Specific Tax Good or service is taxed a fixed amount per unit e.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Spectra</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/AtomicSpectra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/AtomicSpectra/</guid><description>Go Back
Differences in Discrete Energy Levels Key Points:
Unique Spectra: As the discrete energy levels for atoms are fixed and unique to each atom, the discrete energy level differences are also fixed and unique to each element.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Structure</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/AtomicStructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/AtomicStructure/</guid><description>Go Back
John Dalton 1803-08: Proposed “Atomic Theory of Matter“
Matter (elements) is composed of small, indivisible, particles called “atoms” All atoms for a given element are identical (same shape, size, mass, chemical properties) Atoms are not created, destroyed or changed into different types in a chemical reaction: a chemical reaction involves the rearrangement, combination or separation of atoms Atoms combine in fixed proportions to form compounds Atom is a sphere Disadvantages</description></item><item><title>Chemistry Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Chemistry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Chemistry/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Close Reading Structure</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/CloseReading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/CloseReading/</guid><description>go back
A way of interpreting a text&amp;rsquo;s main meaning/message You do not need a conclusion for this, but can include one if you wish Introduction Short introduction(not like an essay) What is the text about?</description></item><item><title>Covalent Bonding</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/covalent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/covalent/</guid><description>go back
Non-metal atoms involved Covalent bonding: Non-metal atoms share one or more pairrs of electrons by overlapping valence shells to give each a nobel gass structure A covalent bond is a shared pair of electrons There is a force of attraction between the bonding pair of electrons and the nuceli of the atoms at each side Hydrogen atoms only need 2 electrons in their outer level to reach the noble gas structure of helium Octet Rule: Atoms gain, lose or share eelectrons when they combine with other atoms to acquire a stable octet (8) of electrons There are exceptions: $SF_6$ and $BCl_3$ Properties Non-conductors of electricity Electrons are localised in the electron cloud or as bonding pairs Therefore, they are immobile, and cannot conduct charge Bad conductors of heat No free particles that can move from one end of the particle to another, carrying kinetic energy (temperature) Thus, it is a bad conductor of heat Soft Only weak intermolecular forces exist between the molecules and so these molecules can be easily separated and rearranged when a force is applied, making them soft Low melting/boiling point Only weak intermolecular forces exist between the molecules Small amount of energy is need to overcome these bonds, and there is a low melting/boiling point These increase with molecular size, which increases the strength of the bonds Note: These are for Covalent Molecular Structures, not Covalent Network Structures, which you do not need to know</description></item><item><title>Economics Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Economics/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Electronic Configuration</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/ElectronicConfig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/ElectronicConfig/</guid><description>Electrons are arranged in energy levels or shells
n is the principal quantum number or shell number</description></item><item><title>Force and Free Body Diagrams</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Force/</guid><description>go back
Force: Mass (kg) x acceleration ($ms^{-2}$), units in Newtons (N)
Vector Quantity, include direction $$ f=ma $$</description></item><item><title>Gothic Literature</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Goth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Goth/</guid><description>go back
The Dark Ages Alternatively the Middle Ages (approx. 800 AD - 1500) A time of “intellectual darkness” Feudal societies resign many citizens to the uneducated peasantry Artistic and cultural developments of Antiquity perceived to have halted Emphasis on logic and reason gives way to increased reliance on dogmatic systems of belief Church of England Superstitions or folk beliefs Also historically associated with violence, depravity “Gothic” becomes a bad word</description></item><item><title>How to Study for Year 11 Literature</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Study/</guid><description>You should be doing at least 2 hours study per week for Lit in Year 11. Listed below are some of the things you should be doing in that time.</description></item><item><title>Important Variables to Know</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Variable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Variable/</guid><description>go back
Vectors (require direction and magnitude) s: Displacement
in meters v: Velocity $ms^{-1}$, meters per second F: force Newtons J: work Joules i: Impulse $kg\ ms^{-1}$, kg per meters per second W: watts p: Momentum $kg\ ms^{-1}$, kg per meters per second N: Newtons a: Acceleration $ms^{-2}$, meters per, seconds squared g: Gravity, 9.</description></item><item><title>Intermolecular Forces</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Intermolecular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Intermolecular/</guid><description>go back
Forces between molecules Allotropes: Different physical forms of the same element E.g., carbon, diamond, graphite Gases: Very weak attraction between particles Liquid: stronger attraction between particles Solids: Very strong attraction between particles Also known as Van Der Waal&amp;rsquo;s forces Dispersion Forces Forces existing between 2 polar molecules Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between 2 oppositely charged temporary/induced dipoles Electrons move randomly; thus dipoles are temporary, as their charges is based on these electrons, as their localisation is temporary Molecules with dipoles can polarise other molecules and make them form temporary dipoles - these are called induced dipoles This ESF of attraction between the temporary and induced dipoles are known as dispersion forces These are temporary, as electrons move randomly, therefore the dipoles form, break apart, and reform randomly Permanent Dipole-Dipole Forces present between 2 polar molecules Formed from the electrostatic force of attraction between 2 net dipoles; i.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Economics</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Introduction2Economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Introduction2Economics/</guid><description>Go back
Macro-economics vs Micro-economics Macro-economics and Micro-economics are 2 of the largest subdivisions of the study of economics Micro- refers to the observation of small economics units Effects of government regulations on individual markets and consumer decision making Macro- refers to the “big picture” version of economics How interest rates are determined Why some economics grow faster than others Micro-economics Individual markets Consumers Producers/firrms Government How their actions influence decisions and individual markets Utility maximisation/satisfaction Firm production and profit maximisation Individual market equilibrium Effects of government regulations on individual markets Externalities and other side effects Macro-economics The big picture Focuses on aggregate production and consumption in an economy Effects of general taxes such as income and sales taxes on output and prices Causes of economics upswings and downturns Effects of monetary and fiscal policies on economics health Effects of, and process for, determining interest rates Causes for some economies growing faster than other economies Uses GDP (Gross Domestic Product: monetary value of all finished goods and services within a give time period) and goods and services by their market price Inflation, unemployment rate, GDP Scarcity We have unlimited wants and limited resources to satisfy those wwants There is a scarcity of resources Resources have alternative uses Basic Economic Problem (BEP) BEP is every and affects us all Due to the problem of “relative scarcity” Scarcity relative to our wants Resources may be abundant but wants are unlimited, how are the resources allocated: relative scarcity Due to scarcity, we are forced to make choices Resources cannot be used for all human wants We must choose We have unlimited wants, but there is a scarcity of resources to satisfy those wants.</description></item><item><title>Ionic Bonding</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/ionic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/ionic/</guid><description>go back
Electrostatic force of attraction between oppositely charged(cations and anions) ions in a network
Consists of a metal and a non-metal combined together</description></item><item><title>Linear Equations</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Lines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Lines/</guid><description>go back
The equation for a straight line is $$y=mx+c$$
y and x are values on the graph</description></item><item><title>Literature Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Literature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Literature/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Market Efficiency</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/MarketEfficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/MarketEfficiency/</guid><description>Go back
Consumer Surplus: Highest price consumers are willing to pay for a good minus the price actually paid</description></item><item><title>Market Equilibrium and Price Determination</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/MarPri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/MarPri/</guid><description>go back
Market Equilibrium: State of a market that has no tendency to change Equilibrium Price: Price a which $Q_{supplied}=Q_{demanded}$ There is no surplus or shortage in a market equilibrium There is no pressure to change price The market clears, i.</description></item><item><title>Market Failure</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/marketfailure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/marketfailure/</guid><description>We learned that in a free competitive market, when the price of a good adjusts to make quantity demanded equal to quantity supplied, the equilibrium quantity reflects the &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; or optimal allocation of resources to the production of that good</description></item><item><title>Metallic Bonding</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/metal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/metal/</guid><description>Electrostatic forces of attraction between cations of metal and a sea of delocalised electrons
Metal atoms are packed together in a giant metallic lattice</description></item><item><title>Metaphysical Poetry</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/10MetaphysicalPoetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/10MetaphysicalPoetry/</guid><description>go back
Context: Renaissance Period
Classical art/subjects, e.g. romance, sonnets, poetry 17th Century England Church Believed in Christianity Elizabethan Poetry,Shakespeare Metaphysical language Meta: Greek for beyond Physics: physical nature BEYOND physical nature E.</description></item><item><title>Methods Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Methods/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Momentum and Impulse</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Momentum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Momentum/</guid><description>go back
Momentum Momentum: Mass (kg) x Velocity (m/s) , units are $kg$ $ms^{-1}$
Vector quantity, include direction $$ p = mv $$</description></item><item><title>Motion Equations</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Motion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Motion/</guid><description>go back
SUVAT Equations S: Displacement: m
U: Initial Velocity: $ms^{-1}$
V: Final Velocity: $ms^{-1}$
A: Acceleration: $ms^{-2}$
T: Time: s</description></item><item><title>Narrative Conventions and Language Devices</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Conventions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Conventions/</guid><description>go back
Narrative conventions: Characterisation (SAAO)
Setting (physical, context)
Point of View
1st person I, me 2nd person You, we, us E.</description></item><item><title>Nuclear Physics</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/NuclearPhysics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/NuclearPhysics/</guid><description>Atoms Central part of an atom is the nucleus Consists of: Neutrons No charge: 0 Relative Atomic Mass: 1 Protons Positive Charge + Relative Atomic Mass: 1 Collectively called nucleons Almost identical in mass and size Most of an atom is empty space that is only occupied by electrons Any change in the amount of protons changes the element  Electrons Negative Charge: - Relative Atomic Mass: 1/1836 Orbit nucleus at high speeds $$^A_ZX$$ A: Mass number No.</description></item><item><title>Organic Chemistry</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/10organic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/10organic/</guid><description>Energy Energy: capacity to do work Work: exertion of force overcoming resistance or producing molecular change Exothermic reaction gives out heat Endothermic reaction absorbs heat Direct + Indirect uses of Energy Direct</description></item><item><title>Patterns/Trends in the Periodic Table</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Patterns/</guid><description>Go Back
Reactivity of Group 1 Metals increases as there are more valence electron shells
ESF: Electrostatic Forces of Attraction</description></item><item><title>Periodicity</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Periodicity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/Periodicity/</guid><description>Physical Properties Boiling point Melting point Hardness Conductivity Brittle Malleable Ductile Allotropes of Carbon Carbon has 4 valence electrons Can bond to itself, and forms a variety of different compounds Diamond Non-conductive of electricity High melting/boiling point Graphite 2D hexagonal layers Mobile delocalised electrons that are free to move within layers Dispersion forces between layers Conductive of electricity Buckyball - (Buckminster fulleren z ) Not conductive of electricity Used as a dry lubricant</description></item><item><title>Permutations and Combinations</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/PerCom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/PerCom/</guid><description>Permutations n! is equal to $n\times(n-1)\times(n-2)\times(n-3)&amp;hellip;\times2\times1$ When order is important Think of it as arranging items Notation is $^nP_r$ Where we are arranging r objects from n objects This equation can be written as: $$ \frac{n!</description></item><item><title>Permutations and Combinations</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/PerCom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/PerCom/</guid><description>Permutations n! is equal to $n\times(n-1)\times(n-2)\times(n-3)&amp;hellip;\times2\times1$ When order is important Think of it as arranging items Notation is $^nP_r$ Where we are arranging r objects from n objects This equation can be written as: $$ \frac{n!</description></item><item><title>Perth Pokémon Oceania Regional Championships 2023</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Writings/perth2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Writings/perth2023/</guid><description>go back
Written on 3rd-4th April 2023.
Introduction So&amp;hellip;as a hobby, I play a funny little game called Pokémon. You might&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it.</description></item><item><title>Physics as a Human Endeavor</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/humanstuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/humanstuff/</guid><description>Car Safety Holding the mass of the car and the total change in velocity constant (as when braking you will always be breaking from a set speed), the impulse for the car will be constant as well, because $I=m\Delta v$ When a car breaks suddenly, as the non-seat-belt-wearing passengers have a tendency to maintain their path (inertia), they are flung forward until they collide with the front; at this point, a force acts on them to slow them down along with the car Crumple Zones When 2 cars collide, the crumple zone contracts (absorbing the impact force) and thus a retarding force is applied on the car through a larger amount of time.</description></item><item><title>Physics Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Physics/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>Pokemon Sprites from Gen 1-8</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/poke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/poke/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;My question is why? Why have you done this? For what purpose?&amp;rdquo; - Nyasha Ncube</description></item><item><title>Price Elasticity of Demand (PED)</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/PED/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/PED/</guid><description>go back
Measures the responsiveness of quantity demanded of a good to a change in its price, ceteris paribus Depends on what %Δ you want, use price for price, and QD for QD Elasticity declines along demand curve as we move towards quantity axis Elasticities When price elasticity is between $0$ and $-1$, demand is price inelastic</description></item><item><title>Price Elasticity of Supply (PES)</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/PES/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/PES/</guid><description>go back
Measures responsiveness of quantity supplied of a good to a change in its price, ceteris paribus When a price change results in a more than proportionate change in quantity supplied, SS is price elastic</description></item><item><title>Probability</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Probability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Probability/</guid><description>go back
A measure of the likelihood of an event occurring $P(A)$ is the probability of A occurring Theoretical Probability: theory probability, e.</description></item><item><title>Quadratic Equations</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Quadratics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Methods/Quadratics/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Romanticism Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Rom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Literature/Rom/</guid><description>go back
Ego-centric point of view Context Romanticism: attitude or intellectual orientation that characterised many works of literature, paintings, music, architecture and criticism in Western civilisation over a period from the late 18th century to the mid-19th century Can be seen as a rejection of the precepts of order, calm, harmony, balance, idealisation, and rationality that typified late 18th century Neo-classicism in particular Also a reaction against the Enlightenment and against 18th Century The Romantic Movement Freedom of the individual Rejection of restricting social conventions and political rule Fight for rights of the common man Emphasis on emotions and the imagination over reason and logic Free spontaneous action over controlled calculated behaviour Valorisation of the wilderness The “noble savage” Savage meaning people from other, non-Euro places Revival of interest on folklore and legends Chivalry As an aesthetic philosophy, Romanticism engages with these key concepts:</description></item><item><title>Scalars and Vectors</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/ScaVec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/ScaVec/</guid><description>go back
Scalars Value only with magnitude Distance (s), in m Speed (|v| or v), in $ms^{-1}$ Time (t), in s $$ |v| = \frac{s}{t} $$</description></item><item><title>Science Inquiry Skills</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/SIS/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/SIS/</guid><description>go back
Accuracy: How close your experimentally derived number is to the “true” or “real” quantity being measured
Precision: How the repeat values or a given trial are to each other, OR the fineness of the scale on the instrument being used to take measurements</description></item><item><title>Sister Sites</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/townsites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/townsites/</guid><description>Dasindu&amp;rsquo;s Site Edward&amp;rsquo;s Site Christian&amp;rsquo;s Site Shan-Mei&amp;rsquo;s Site</description></item><item><title>Specialist Notes</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Specialist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Subjects/Specialist/</guid><description>THESE NOTES ARE IN ORDER OF THE CONTENT COVERED, WITH INITIAL CONTENT AT THE TOP, AND FINAL CONTENT AT THE BOTTOM!</description></item><item><title>The Theory of Demand</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Demand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Demand/</guid><description>Go back
Markets Where Buyers and Sellers meet in order to exchange money for goods They do not always meet in person Goods can be bought by consumers and sold by suppliers in online markets, e.</description></item><item><title>The Theory of Proof</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/TheTheoryofProof/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/TheTheoryofProof/</guid><description>Basically a mathematical way of proving a statement E.g., If a is even and b is even, prove that a+b is even We must use notation, and definitions Notation Set $\mathbb{R}$ Real Numbers, all rational and irrational numbers $\mathbb{Q}$ Rational numbers, all numbers that can be expressed as a fraction $\mathbb{Z}$ Integers, all whole numbers $\mathbb{N}$ All natural numbers, i.</description></item><item><title>The Theory of Supply</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Supply/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Economics/Supply/</guid><description>Go back
Amount of a good or service a producer is willing and able to sell in a given period of time, at a given price, ceteris paribus Objective of producers is to maximise profits $Profit = Revenue-Costs$ Law of Supply: In a given time period, the quantity supplied of a good or service is directly related to its price, ceteris paribus Produces aim to maximise profit, while consumers aim to maximise satisfaction Individual Supply: Refers to the sum of the individual supply for a good or service by all the producers in the market Market Supply: Refers to the sum of all the individual supply for a good or service by all the producers in the market Exceptional Supply Curves Vertical supply curve No matter the price, the same quantity is supplied E.</description></item><item><title>Town Analogy</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/town/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Info/town/</guid><description>I sell books, and am a tour guide in my spare time.</description></item><item><title>Vectors</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/Vectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Specialist/Vectors/</guid><description>[!info] Dr Pearce
Some of the images were from my teacher, Dr Pearce.
Value with Direction and Magnitude Vector Diagrams Vectors can be represented in a diagram Arrows are used to represent vector quantities Must be some vector on each side Must be resolved Adding Vectors For 2 Vectors A and B</description></item><item><title>VSEPR - Valence Shell Electron Repulsion Theory</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/VSEPR/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Chemistry/VSEPR/</guid><description>go back
VSEPR model can predict the structure of most molecules and polyatomic ions in which the central atom is a non-metal Also works for some structures in which the central atom is a metal VSEPR builds on Lewis Electron Dot Structures Lewis structures alone predict only connectivity while the Lewis structure and VSEPR together can predict the geometry of each atom in a molecule Key Concepts The 4 pairs of electrons around a central atom repel each other Pairs of electrons arrange themselves so they are as far apart as possible The repulsion between lone pairs is greater than the repulsion between bonding Bent&amp;rsquo;s angle is 104.</description></item><item><title>Waves</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Waves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/Waves/</guid><description>go back
Waves: The transfer of energy from one place to another without the net displacement of matter</description></item><item><title>Work, Force and Powewr</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/WorkForcePower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/11Physics/WorkForcePower/</guid><description>go back
Energy: Ability to do work Measured in Joules (J) Work: $Fs$ = $Nm$ $$ E_k=\frac{1}{2}mv^2 $$</description></item><item><title>Writings</title><link>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Writings/Writings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://supaqwerty.github.io/notes-dump/Writings/Writings/</guid><description>Philosophical writings and recounts of things in my life
Perth Pokémon Regional Championships 2023</description></item></channel></rss>