<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Harrypotters on</title><link>https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/</link><description>Recent content in Harrypotters on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Diagon Alley</title><link>https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/diagon-alley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/diagon-alley/</guid><description>go back
Congratulations! You&amp;rsquo;ve made it to Diagon Alley!
This is just a fun minigame I made</description></item><item><title>The Leaky Cauldron</title><link>https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/the-leaky-cauldron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nottaro.github.io/notes-dump/harrypotter/the-leaky-cauldron/</guid><description>this is crashing my laptop
口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口 口</description></item></channel></rss>